imtservices.com 2016-03-14

# InsureMyTrip Privacy, Security and Legal Policies

### Introduction

This statement discloses the privacy practices of IMT SERVICES CORPORATION (IMT) and its owned and operated web sites which are located at URLs: InsureMyTrip.com and InsureMyTraveler.com. When you visit a web site, you expect to know what personal information is collected; how the information is used; with whom the information may be shared; what choices are available to you regarding collection, use, distribution and disclosure of the information; the kind of security procedures that are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of this information under the web site's control and the method for accessing the personal information that we have collected about you and request that such information be rectified or deleted. Questions regarding this statement, access requests or inaccuracies in the information should be directed to customercare@insuremytrip.com. We will respond to your inquiry or request within thirty (30) days.

This privacy statement is an Agreement. If you choose to provide personal information to us, the handling of your personal information will be governed by the terms and conditions contained herein. If you do not agree to the terms and conditions contained herein, please do not provide IMT with any personal information.

### Overview

IMT encourages you to visit our web sites knowing that you have complete control over your personal information. You can browse our pages without having to tell us who you are or revealing any personal information whatsoever. However, if you communicate with our customer service department via online chat, email or phone, you might supply us with personal information such as your name, email address and other contact information. Also, if you decide to purchase travel insurance, the applications will require you to input more information such as name and address, travel arrangements and credit card information in order for us to service you appropriately. We do indicate on these pages of the web site that we are collecting this information from you and the purposes for doing so, except where it is obvious. We will not use your personal information for other purposes without notifying you of our intention to do so and obtaining your consent.

IMT is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of any other web sites on the Internet that are hyper-linked to or from our site.

For our Canadian visitors, we endorse and adopt in their entirety, the ten principles of the Canadian Standard Associations' Model Code for Protection of Personal Information.

### Information Gathering

The IMT web sites collect the following information only if you choose to provide it:

  * For a question or request ("Contact Us", "Service" and the "Live Chat" areas): 
    * Name, email address and any comments you make.
  * For a quote: 
    * Coverage limits, dates of travel, age(s) or date(s) of birth for each traveller, destination, trip type, and residency.
  * For a travel policy, on behalf of the insurance carriers, we collect from you and disclose to them the following information: 
    * Name, mailing address, telephone number(s), Email Address, trip deposit date, tour operator, airline and/or cruise line and trip departure hour.
    * Credit Card Information.
  * For user accounts: 
    * Name, email address, and password.

### Using Information Gathered

The information collected when you contact us with a question or a suggestion will only be used to respond to and/or resolve your question.

The information collected for a quote or for a travel policy is used to provide policy quotes and to issue your policy. The information is in turn sent encrypted, only to the insurance company underwriting the policy and the producing agent if applicable. The insurance companies employ standard encryption practices receiving such information.

IMT archives information provided by you for policy quoting and policy issuance on our servers located in the United States. This information is kept electronically, but is internal to IMT and not maintained on the web site. We collect and retain this information in accordance with all applicable laws, including without limitation insurance laws/laws governing insurance carriers.

### Sharing and Disclosing Information Gathered

In general, our sites will only collect data from you that will be used to respond to and/or resolve your question, to provide accurate quotes, and to issue policies.

We do track the domain name, IP address, browser type, and referring IP address of our site visitors through a site-reporting tool that runs on our servers and uses cookies. This information is used internally only to show activity and trends of our site usage.

We do not provide your personal information to mailing lists nor do we sell, share or trade your information to unaffiliated parties. From time to time, we may share your email address with third-party vendors to provide services on our behalf, including but not limited to marketing emails and email distribution of surveys. These vendors are not permitted to share your email address with anyone else nor use the information for any other purpose.

From time to time, we may be required to provide your personal information in response to a court order, subpoena, government investigation, or as otherwise required by law.

### Protecting Information Gathered

IMT uses Secure Socket Layer encryption (SSL) to protect the privacy of your information.

IMT does not control the privacy practices of the companies which we represent; however, all the companies use the information you provide for the purpose of issuing an accurate insurance policy. Quote information is not shared with any of the insurance companies. It is your choice whether to provide personal information to IMT. If you choose to give us the personal information, refer to this privacy statement for an understanding of how that information will be collected, used and/or disclosed or distributed.

You are entitled to access the personal information which we have gathered about you and to request corrections of that information. In order to do so, please direct your request to [customercare @ insuremytrip.com](mailto:customercare@insuremytrip.com) and describe your request or correction.

Please refer to the privacy policy statements of the individual insurance companies for their use of your personal information.

### Updates to the Privacy Policy Statement

We may amend this policy from time to time to keep up with changes in the law or corporate policies. If we make any substantive changes we will notify you by sending a notice to the primary email address you have provided us or by posting a prominent announcement on our webpage.

This privacy policy statement was last updated on July 24, 2013.

When you trust us with your personal information, you can be sure that we're managing that trust responsibly. We closely follow industry standards and best practices to ensure that the security of our data won't be compromised.

### User Security

InsureMyTrip uses Secure Socket Layer encryption (SSL) to protect the privacy of your information. Encryption is a way of scrambling a message or a piece of data so that only a person who has the decryption key can view it. By encrypting your personal information, we're able to make sure no unauthorized persons can see what you've shared with us.

### Physical Security

Our data center is monitored 24/7/365. We use digital surveillance equipment to maintain efficient monitoring, and store all customer data exclusively on servers located within the United States.

### Availability

Our servers have redundant internal and external power supplies. By implementing backup power for our servers, we're able to make sure that data isn't lost due to power service issues in severe weather or other unforeseen circumstances.

### Network Security

Network firewalls are used to restrict traffic and access to sensitive information. We also use intrusion detection systems, which prevent access to our data from outside intruders.

### Storage Security

All data is stored on servers located in the United States. We run backups throughout the day and use an offsite storage system for backup. We also encrypt all information in our backup systems to prevent data from being viewed by unauthorized persons.

If you have any questions about our security policies or what we do to protect you, send us a message at [security @ insuremytrip.com](mailto:security@insuremytrip.com).

### Trademark and Copyright Ownership

The materials on this site, including copyrighted material, service marks, trademarks, trade names and logos, are owned by IMT Services Corporation and/or InsureMyTrip.com or the insurance companies we represent. Copying, reproducing, transmitting or republishing any materials from this site is prohibited, except that you may download the material and print a reference copy for your own personal, non-commercial use. If you download or print a copy of our materials, you must not remove the copyright, trademark or other legal notices from the copy you make. Any other modification or use of the materials on this site violates IMT Services Corporation's and/or InsureMyTrip.com's proprietary rights in the materials unless you first obtain our written consent.

### Jurisdiction

Unless otherwise specified, the materials in our site are presented solely for the purpose of promoting and facilitating the issuance of insurance policies available within The United States of America. The site may contain references to products or services that are not offered or available in the state in which you reside. IMT Services Corporation makes no representation that materials in the site are appropriate or offered in other locations. This site is controlled and operated by IMT Services Corporation from its offices located in the state of Rhode Island, United States of America.

### Disclaimer (No Warranty)

The information and materials contained in this site are provided on an "as is" basis for information purposes only. IMT Services Corporation & InsureMyTrip.com do not warrant the accuracy, adequacy or completeness of the information and materials contained in this site and expressly disclaim liability for any errors or omissions in the information and materials. No warranty of any kind either implied, expressed or statutory, including but not limited to the warranties of non-infringement of third-party rights, title, merchantability, fitness for a particular purpose and freedom from computer virus is given with the information and materials contained in this site.

### Licenses

We sell insurance as an agent or broker by contractual agreements with our partner insurance carriers. Although we transact travel insurance business from our web sites, we maintain offices in Rhode Island, New York and Connecticut. We are also licensed in states as indicated below:

State | Licensee | License  
---|---|---  
Alabama | IMT Services Corporation | A253388  
Alaska | IMT Services Corporation | 33001  
Arizona | IMT Services Corporation | 851456  
Arkansas | IMT Services Corporation | 298013  
California | IMT Services Corporation   
d.b.a. IMT Insurance Services | 0F23551  
Colorado | IMT Services Corporation | 261146  
Connecticut | IMT Services Corporation | 1087383  
Delaware | IMT Services Corporation | 1014865  
District of Columbia | IMT Services Corporation | 2817294  
Florida | IMT Services Corporation | L004939  
Georgia | IMT Services Corporation | 115128  
Hawaii | IMT Services Corporation | 334582  
Idaho | IMT Services Corporation | AB131923  
Illinois | IMT Services Corporation | 113599814  
Indiana | IMT Services Corporation | 37548  
Iowa | IMT Services Corporation | 3254  
Kansas | IMT Services Corporation | 113599814-000  
Kentucky | IMT Services Corporation | 624849  
Louisiana | IMT Services Corporation | 330511  
Maine | IMT Services Corporation | AGN121556  
Maryland | IMT Services Corporation | NPF 99951779  
Massachusetts | IMT Services Corporation | 1834242  
Michigan | IMT Services Corporation | 74472  
Minnesota | IMT Services Corporation | IA-20579310  
Mississippi | IMT Services Corporation | 10002915  
Missouri | IMT Services Corporation | AG802787  
Montana | IMT Services Corporation | 662415  
Nebraska | IMT Services Corporation | 333102  
Nevada | IMT Services Corporation | 18639  
New Hampshire | IMT Services Corporation | 427801  
New Jersey | IMT Services Corporation | 1048629  
New Mexico | IMT Services Corporation | 100001142  
New York | IMT Services Corporation | BR/LA/PC-730861  
North Carolina | IMT Services Corporation | 9814  
North Dakota | IMT Services Corporation | 11-3599814-01  
Ohio | IMT Services Corporation | 33750  
Oklahoma | IMT Services Corporation | 983172  
Oregon | IMT Services Corporation | 816960  
Pennsylvania | IMT Services Corporation | 66270  
Rhode Island | IMT Services Corporation | 1089872  
South Carolina | IMT Services Corporation | 166589  
South Dakota | IMT Services Corporation | C8309  
Tennessee | IMT Services Corporation | 3130  
Texas | IMT Services Corporation | 1365714  
Utah | IMT Services Corporation | 234559  
Vermont | IMT Services Corporation | 1028  
Virginia | IMT Services Corporation | 11-3599814  
Washington | IMT Services Corporation | 211509  
West Virginia | IMT Services Corporation | 3906  
Wisconsin | IMT Services Corporation | 3951  
Wyoming | IMT Services Corporation | 64718  
  
US Territories |   
Licensee |   
License  
Puerto Rico | IMT Services Corporation | 100100859  
  
Province |   
Licensee |   
License  
Alberta | IMT Services Corporation | 6-3119094-2006  
British Columbia | IMT Services Corporation | 165647B735012R1  
Manitoba | IMT Services Corporation | S-28829-772739-2006  
New Brunswick | James N. Grace III | 502181  
Newfoundland & Labrador | IMT Services Corporation | 07-67-IM025-1  
Northwest Territories | James N. Grace III | NT-2006815  
Nova Scotia | IMT Services Corporation | 06 918030 00F1  
Nunavut | James N. Grace III | NU-2006715  
Ontario | IMT Services Corporation | 645M  
Prince Edward Island | James N. Grace III | 6202  
Quebec | IMT Services Corporation | Pending  
Saskatchewan | IMT Services Corporation | 4577  
Yukon | IMT Services Corporation | 0424-17-1762
